A Guide to the Papers of Henry Evans Howell, Jr. 1948-1976
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University Libraries, Old Dominion University
- SERIES VI: NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS
  - Sub-Series D: 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign
    - General, August 16-20, 1973 (Box-folder Box 179, Folder 10)
    - General, August 21-31, 1973 (Box-folder Box 179, Folder 11)
    - General, September 6-10, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 1)
    - General, September 1-5, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 2)
    - General, September 11-15, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 3)
    - General, September 16-17, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 4)
    - General, September 18-20, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 5)
    - General, September 21-25, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 6)
    - General, September 26-30, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 7)
    - General, September, 1973 (undated) (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 8)
    - General, October 1-5, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 9)
    - General, October 6-10, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 10)
    - General, October 11-15, 1973 (Box-folder Box 180, Folder 11)
    - General, October 16-20, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 1)
    - General, October 21-25, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 2)
    - General, October 26-31, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 3)
    - General, October, 1973 (Undated) (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 4)
    - General, November, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 5)
    - General, January, 1972 - June, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 6)
    - General, July-August, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 7)
    - General, September-October, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 8)
    - Clarksville Times, May-June, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 9)
    - The Independent Virginian, March-August, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 10)
    - Richmond Mercury Articles, April-October, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 11)
    - Richmond News Leader, May-June, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 12)
    - Richmond Times-Dispatch, May-July, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 13)
    - Richmond Times Dispatch - "Industrial Development and Review," April 23, 1972 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 14)
    - Roanoke Times, May-June, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 15)
    - Virginian Pilot, May 31 July 14, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 16)
    - Washington Post, May-July, 1973 (Box-folder Box 181, Folder 17)
    - Agency Fee; Agnew; Ballot; Betting; Blacks; Blue Law, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 1)
    - C & P; Campaign Financing; Candidate Debates; Capitol; Cartoons; "Clear Choice"; College Newspapers; Congressional Races (1972), 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 2)
    - Consumer Issues; Flora Crater; Crime; Culture, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 3)
    - Dalton, John; Democrats; Local Democrats; Democratic Party (State), Drugs, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 4)
    - Editorials (Anti-HEH); Education; Endorsements; Energy, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 5)
    - Environment, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 6)
    - Fuel Shortage; General Assembly; General Assembly Session (1973), 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 7)
    - General Assembly Races, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 8)
    - General Campaign, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 9)
    - Mills Godwin, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 10)
    - GOP; Green Springs, 1973 (Box-folder Box 182, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign (General), 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 1)
    - Health; High Cost of Living; Higher Education, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 2)
    - Highway System; Holton, Linwood; Housing, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 3)
    - Henry Howell - General, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 4)
    - HEH & Mills Godwin; HEH Sayings, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 5)
    - Inflation; Justice; Insurance; Kelley, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 6)
    - Labor, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 7)
    - "Law and Order"; Localities; "Loyalty Oath," 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 8)
    - Mass Transit; Michael, J. Harry; Mill Prices; Miller, Andrew, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous; Mortgage Companies; No-Interest Accounts, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 10)
    - Norfolk Savings & Loan Closing, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 11)
    - Obenshain, Richard; Patriotism; Parties, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 12)
    - Political Gatherings; Poverty; Presidential Election (1972); Prisons, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 13)
    - Public Employees; Public Health Service Hospital, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 14)
    - Rally; Regionalization; Republicans (Virginia), 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 15)
    - "Right to Work"; Sales Tax on Food, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 183, Folder 16)
    - Secondary Races - Lieutenant Governor; Attorney General, 1973 (Box-folder Box 184, Folder 1)
    - Senior Citizens; State Government, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 184, Folder 2)
    - Taxation (Miscellaneous); UMW Journal; Transportation, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 184, Folder 3)
    - VEPCO; Virginia Mood; Voter Registration; Watergate, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 184, Folder 4)
    - Women, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 184, Folder 5)
    - Youth, 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 184, Folder 6)
- SERIES VII: PICTORIAL RECORDS 1953-1969
  - 1953 General Assembly Campaign: Transparency for T.V. Ad, 1953 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 1)
  - 1963 General Assembly Campaign: Howell Portrait (Elsa Spival Possible Photographer), 1963 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 2)
  - Henry Howell Photo with Governor Albertis Harrison, 1964 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 3)
  - 1967 State Senate Campaign; Miscellaneous Photos of Henry Howell, 1967 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 4)
  - 1965 State Senate Campaign; Negatives of Howell Photos; Photo Used in Campaign Literature, 1965 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 5)
  - Norfolk First Campaign; Photo of Billboard (Thanking Supporters), 1967 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 6)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Henry Howell Portraits: Photos; Proofs, 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 7)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Howell Family Portraits: Photos; Proofs, 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 8)
  - Announcement Rally Photos, June, 1968 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 9)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Howell for Governor Rally, 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 10)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Howell for Governor Rally, 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 11)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Senator Howell's Arrival at Spencer Airport (Martinsville, Virginia), July 20, 1968 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Beach Meeting; College Students for Howell, September, 1968 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 13)
  - Charlottesville Meeting (Proofs from Rey Barry), February 1, 1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 14)
  - Roanoke Campaign - Photos Taken by Wayne Deal, 1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Photos of Campaigning, 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Photos (5" x 7" or less), 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Negatives, 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 18)
  - Photos, Negatives for Campaign Literature, 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 19)
  - 35 mm. Slide of Henry Howell, 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 20)
  - Film of Howell Commercials (Lois-Holland-Calloway Agency), 1969 (Box-folder Box 185, Folder 21)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Cartoon Submitted by Howell Supporter, 1969 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 1)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Campaign Photos - Fred Pollard; W. Carrington Thompson, 1969 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 2)
  - 1970 George Rawlings U.S. Senate Campaign; Miscellaneous Photos, 1970 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 3)
  - 1971 Lieutenant Governor Campaign; Proofs, Negatives of Henry Howell Campaigning, 1971 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 4)
  - 1971 Lieutenant Governor Campaign; 35 nun. Slides -Henry Howell Campaigning, 1971 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 5)
  - Lieutenant Governorship; Miscellaneous Photos, 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 6)
  - Lieutenant Governorship; Photos from Steve Vlahovich, October, 1972 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 7)
  - Henry Howell Portraits, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 8)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Henry Howell Portraits, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 9)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Henry Howell Portraits, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 10)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Howell Family Portraits, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 11)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Announcement Rally - Photos of Possible Entertainers, April, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 12)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Announcement Rally -Miscellaneous Photos, April, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 13)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Autographed Picture with Johnny Kerr (Virginia Squires G.M.), 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 14)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Howell party given by Frances and Sydney Lewis, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 15)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Miscellaneous Photos, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 16)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Miscellaneous Proofs, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 17)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Miscellaneous Proofs, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 18)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Miscellaneous Proofs, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 19)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Negatives for Campaign Literature, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 20)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Plate for Printing Campaign Literature, 1973 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 21)
- SERIES VIII: SOUND RECORDINGS
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Henry Howell Speech - Jefferson Hotel, Richmond (Tape Reel), September 6, 1968 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 22)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Beeper System Messages for Radio Stations (Tape Reel), 1969 (Box-folder Box 186, Folder 23)
  - 1970 Joe Fitzpatrick Congressional Campaign; Tape Reel (Largely Blank), 1970 (Box-folder Box 187, Folder 1)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign, Howell Campaign Song: "Howell Cannonball" - Senator Charles Waddell (45 rpm Record), 1973 (Box-folder Box 187, Folder 2)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign: "Howell Cannonball" - Senator Charles Waddell (Cassette; Tape Reel) (Box-folder Box 187, Folder 3)
- SERIES IX: MEMORABILIA 1973
  - Authorizations to Plead Cases in U.S. District Court (Norfolk); Virginia Supreme Court (Richmond), 1947, 1949 (Box-folder Box 187, Folder 4)
  - 1964 Democratic National Convention Souvenir Plaque for Delegates, 1964 (Box-folder Box 187, Folder 5)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign, Miscellaneous Campaign Buttons, 1969 (Box-folder Box 187, Folder 6)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign; Rubber Stamp for Howell Headquarters (Maritime Tower), 1969 (Box-folder Box 187, Folder 7)
  - 1973 Gubernatorial Campaign; Postage Meter from Howell Headquarters, 1973 (Box-folder Box 187, Folder 8)
- SERIES X: FILE CARDS
  - Sub-Series A: 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign
    - Boothe for Senate Volunteer Cards - 1966 (Box-folder Box 188)
    - Volunteer Cards Boothe for Senate (Norfolk) (Box-folder Box 189)
    - Norfolk First Campaigns (1966-1967) (Box-folder Box 189)
    - McCarthy Petition Signers in Virginia (1968) (Box-folder Box 190)
    - McCarthy Petition Signers in Virginia (1968) (Box-folder Box 191)
    - McCarthy Petition Signers in Virginia (1968) (Box-folder Box 192)
    - Virginia Vote Flow Survey (Box-folder Box 193)
    - Precinct Cards (1968) (Box-folder Box 193)
    - Information Cards (Box-folder Box 194)
- SERIES XI: SPEECHES
  - 1953 Democratic Primary, May-July, 1953 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 1)
  - General (Including 1959 Democratic Primary), 1959-1960 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 2)
  - General (Including 1961 Democratic Primary), 1961 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 3)
  - General, 1962 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 4)
  - General (Including 1963 Democratic Primary), 1963 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 5)
  - General, January-June, 1964 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 6)
  - General, July-December, 1964 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 7)
  - General (Including 1965 State Senate Race), January-March, 1965 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 8)
  - General (Including 1965 State Senate Race), May, 1965 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 9)
  - General (Including 1965 State Senate Race), June, 1965 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 10)
  - General (Including 1965 State Senate Race), July- December, 1965 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 11)
  - General, January-July, 1966 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 12)
  - General, August-December, 1966 (Box-folder Box 195, Folder 13)
  - General (Including 1967 State Senate Race), January-March, 1967 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 1)
  - General (Including 1967 State Senate Race), April-June, 1967 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 2)
  - General (Including 1967 State Senate Race), July- December, 1967 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 3)
  - General, January-March, 1968 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 4)
  - General, April-June, 1968 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 5)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign, June-September, 1968 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 6)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign, October-December, 1968 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 7)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign, January-February, 1969 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 8)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign, March-June 20, 1969 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 9)
  - "The Finest of Tomorrow" (Excerpts from Various Speeches), June 20, 1969 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 10)
  - 1969 Gubernatorial Campaign, July-August, 1969 (Box-folder Box 196, Folder 11)
  - General, September-December, 1969 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 1)
  - General, 1970 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 2)
  - General, January-March, 1971 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 3)
  - General, April-July, 1971 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 4)
  - 1971 Lieutenant Governor Campaign, July-November, 1971 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 5)
  - Lieutenant Governorship - Inaugural Address, December 4, 1971 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 6)
  - Lieutenant Governorship, December 1971 - February 1972 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 7)
  - Lieutenant Governorship, March, 1972 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 8)
  - Lieutenant Governorship, April-May, 1972 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 9)
  - Lieutenant Governorship, June-July, 1972 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 10)
  - Lieutenant Governorship, August-December, 1972 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 11)
  - Lieutenant Governorship, 1973 (Box-folder Box 197, Folder 12)
  - August-December, 1972 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 1)
  - January-March, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 2)
  - April, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 3)
  - May, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 4)
  - June 1-15, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 5)
  - June 16-30, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 6)
  - July, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 7)
  - August, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 8)
  - August 16-31, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 9)
  - September 1-15, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 10)
  - September 16-30, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 11)
  - Betty Howell Speeches, June-October, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 12)
  - October, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 13)
  - November, 1973 (Box-folder Box 198, Folder 14)
- SERIES XII: POLITICAL PAPERS 1974-1976
  - General, 1974 (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 1)
  - General, January-April, 1975 (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 2)
  - General, May-December, 1975 (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 3)
  - General, 1976 (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 4)
  - General, 1974-1976 (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 5)
  - Legal-Case File: Howell vs. NBC (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 6)
  - 1977 Gubernatorial Campaign: Report of Campaign Contributions and Expenditures (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 7)
  - 1977 Gubernatorial Campaign: Report of Campaign Contributions and Expenditures (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 8)
  - 1977 Gubernatorial Campaign: Report of Campaign Contributions and Expenditures (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 9)
  - 1977 Gubernatorial Campaign: Report of Campaign Contributions and Expenditures (Box-folder Box 199, Folder 10)